RG 074:030, Walter Collyer Faxon Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
Water Collyer Faxon genealogical papers
1746-1912
bulk 1893-1912
Connecticut State Library
Faxon, Walter C. (Walter Collyer)
.5 cubic feet
Genealogical notes, correspondence, patriotic society memberships and photographs.
RG074_030
T003240
Biographical Note
Walter Collyer Faxon was born in Hartford on July 18, 1856 to Hiram and Margaret M. (Collyer) Faxon. He graduated from Hartford High School in 1874. He married Nellie A. White of Windsor on May 23, 1877. Faxon died at his home in Hartford on November 13, 1920.
In April, 1874 Faxon began his employment at the Travelers Insurance Company where he worked in the accident department for seventeen years. In 1891, he moved to Aetna Life Insurance Comapny when that company started its accident and liability department. Four years later he was made assistant secretary and then secretary in 1902. In 1905 he was made vice-president and in 1908 was elected vice-president and director. He was also a president of Accident Underwriters and a director of the Automobile Insurance Company of Hartford.
Faxon was a member of the Connecticut Historical Society, the Society of Colonial Wars, The Order of Colonial Governors, the Society of Mayflower Descendants, in which he had been a secretary, the Order of Founders and Patriots of America, in which he held a high office, the Sons of the Revolution and the Sons of the American Revolution. He also had membership in the Hartford Club, the Hartford Golf Club, the Republican Club and the Congregational Club.
Faxon was descended from Governor William Bradford of Plymouth through the Adams, Collins, Terry and Olcott families and from Richard Warren through the Church and Olcott families. Other ancestors included: Francis Elliot, Rev. Solomon Stoddard, Rev. John Wareham, John Pantry, John Norton, John Stanley, George Stocking, William Sprague, Anthony Eams, Thomas Bunce and Thomas Wells.
Source: "Associates Mourn W.C. Faxon's Death." Hartford Courant, 1920 November 14, 4.
Scope and Content
Much of the correspondence pertains to the Read and Snow families from the effort to prove Nellie A. Faxon's Mayflower descent. Most of the material related to patriotic societies concerns Mrs. Faxon. Included are her application and membership certificate to the Daughters of the American Revolution; correspondence concerning her membership in the Daughters of Founders and Patriots of America, as well as by-laws of that organization; applications to the Society of Mayflower Descendents along with correspondence regarding the whereabouts of her genealogical chart; and applications to the Society of Sons of the American Revolution. Also present are Walter C. Faxon's membership certificates to the Society of Colonial Wars and the Society of the Sons of the American Revolution. Other items in the collection include correspondence and membership lists related to Mrs. Faxon's involvement with the YMCA Woman's Auxiliary; a genealogy chart that shows Walter C. Faxon's paternal lines; historical documents including a number of deeds from Lyme, Conn. dated 1746 to 1801; and photographs of both Walter C. and Nellie A. Faxon.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Persons:
Faxon, Walter C. (Walter Collyer)
Places:
Connecticut -- Genealogy
Subjects:
Faxon, Nellie A.; Deeds -- Connecticut -- Lyme
Document Types:
Certificates; Clippings; Correspondence; Genealogies
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The date of receipt of this collection is unknown.
Container List
- Papers, 1746-1912; bulk 1893-1912
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - General, 1894-1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Snow and Read families, 1895-1909, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Snow and Read families from James Allen Kibbe, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Societies (Box 1)
    - Delineator pages, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Daughters of Founders and Patriots of America, 1901-1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Society of Colonial Wars, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Society of Mayflower Descendents, 1912, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Society of Sons of the American Revolution, 1894, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - YMCA Woman's Auxiliary, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Genealogy notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Genealogy charts, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Historical documents (Box 1)
    - Lyme, Conn. deeds, 1746-1801 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1797-1863, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - News clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)